Hey Jordan, congratulations. Welcome to
Chicago. Um, it seems like you've got a
pretty unique athletic background with
family members who are big-time
athletes. Uh, we were just talking to
one of the area scouts and he was saying
that your grandmother was a swimmer,
your grandfather was a was a weight
lifter, bodybuilder. Is that correct?
>> Yes. So, I'm fortunate to come from a
really athletic background. My
grandfather was a five-time Mr. South
Africa um bodybuilder, best bodybuilder
in South Africa. Compete against Arnold
in the Mr. universe competition and
placed sixth that year. And then my
grandmother, she was a national swimmer
for South Africa and she held multiple
South African swimming records and
represented South Africa in the Empire
Games as along with her um her brother
as well.
>> Okay, that's very cool. Um obviously
lineage there. I mean are there other
family members who are athletes like
yourself who played college ball in any
sport?
>> Uh no no ma'am. Sorry. This is my f this
I'm a first generation in America.
John,
>> hey Jordan, congratulations. Um, can you
uh, like you said, first generation
America. Can you tell us a story of how
you got into American football once you
got over here?
>> Yes, sir. Definitely. I've always loved
the physicality of sport. I used to love
playing rugby, wrestling, and I've
always loved the physicality of it. So,
started playing football my 10th grade
year. I was a wide receiver and then
transitioned over to middle linebacker
my junior and senior year. It sounds
like you made some uh several position
changes over the years. Is that right?
>> Yeah. Yes, sir. Yes, sir. I did.
>> What What was it like just trying to
find find the right spot for you all all
these years?
>> No, definitely. You know, my body just
kept evolving. Like I was small my first
year. I was a wide receiver, then middle
linebacker, then defensive end, then DT
tackle. So, just my body kept evolving
and it's been awesome to play
everything. I feel like it adds a lot of
value to me. You know, playing middle
linebacker like helped me with my
vision, I feel like, in my game.
Larry,
>> congratulations. Welcome to Chicago. Um,
I understand that you didn't start
playing football right away when you
came over to the United States. You
played baseball and basketball. What was
your introduction to football? Did you
know anything about it in South Africa?
When did you start watching it? Like,
how did you get introduced to the sport?
>> Uh, yes, sir. So, I grew up watching um
movies. I I remember watching the movie
where it's the um I believe it was the
Eagles that had um the try out for and
one of the fans ended up making a team.
I was like yeah I had that on DVD so I'd
watch that like over and over when I was
a kid and I really fell in love with the
sport through that.
>> Sean,
>> so what's your uh you know understanding
of like how you can fit into the Dline
here in Chicago?
>> No definitely you know you guys have a
lot of talent. And I feel like I'm able
to bring some of the pieces that you
guys um have, you know, I feel like I'm
able to dive deep into backfields and
make plays and I feel like you guys are
a very aggressive front. So that's
something that really fits me.
>> Bill,
>> thank you. Uh congratulations, Jordan.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> Two-part question. Uh one, what um
particular physical attributes do you
think lend yourself to the position? And
then the second part is can
>> Sorry. Well, can you repeat the first
part? It cut out.
>> Oh, yeah. I'm just wondering about um
your physical traits, how you see those
um playing into your position.
>> Yes, sir. Definitely.
>> The second part is uh if you can talk
about your story of how you came to
America and your cultural adjustment on,
you know, like how that happened.
>> Yes, sir. Definitely. You know, I feel
like um I got all the traits you need
for a defensive tackle. I set the
all-time Penn State squad record when I
was at Penn State. I bro jumped 911 and
I um jumped 36 and I benched 35. So I've
always taken pride in the weight room
from I feel like, you know, when I was
at Penn State, I never um broke into the
starting spot, but I knew that my
opportunity would one day come through.
So I made sure everything I could do in
my preparation. So I take a lot of pride
in my preparation, sir. And I would say
um so I was born in Jansburg, South
Africa, lived there all my life until I
was 10. and my family decided to move
over with me and my brothers just for
the chance of a better economic chance,
just for a better future. Sir
>> Courtney
>> Jordan, two-part here, two things that
have nothing to do with each other. The
first, what would you say your best
athletic trait is?
>> I'll definitely say my explosiveness.
You know, I feel like that's something I
pride myself in being able to be
stronger point of attack. Like with my
brawl jump and my vert, that's something
I really take pride in. Every day I'm
training, I'm trying to go as fast as I
can.
>> And I believe I read that you own a
laundromat in Atlanta. Was that like the
How did that come to be? Was that using
you using NIL funds? Was that like how
did you start a business while you were
still in college?
>> No, definitely. Fortunately, I had my
family's help for that. And you know, my
dad has always preached to me that um
life-changing money is only
life-changing money if you put it to
use. So, the first thing we did, we
wanted to look for something that was
passive income so I could set up my
future because, you know, I plan on
playing football until I'm 45, but you
know, um you never know like what can
happen in football. So, I just wanted to
prepare myself.
>> Sean,
>> just to follow up on that, why why a
laundromat? You could jump into a
million different businesses. Why why a
laundromat?
>> I wanted to do something that would help
the community. We're in a very lowincome
place and we do a lot of wash and fold
services for homeless shelters and
everything. I just take pride in being
able to give back to my community and
it's also something that's passive. So
something that's hands off that I don't
really have to worry about.
>> Last two, Pat,
>> you interested in expanding to Illinois?
>> 100%.
with uh
how do you think growing up over
overseas and moving to a new place and
having to experience that and find your
way could help you here moving to a new
place, you know, having new co-workers
in all of that?
>> No, definitely 100%. You know, my whole
life I've been I've lived in a few
places. I lived in South Africa, then I
went to Iowa Western, then Penn State,
then back down to Georgia Tech. in every
single place I went to. I've feel like
I've learned valuable lessons and I'm
just honored for the everywhere I've
been and I just can't wait to be up
there.
>> Last one, Phil.
>> Jordan, you you referenced earlier about
your body evolving? Um, want to kind of
know kind of a chicken, egg, and egg
thing. Was it because you were changing
positions or was it because, you know,
you were just naturally gaining weight?
And then the second part of that,
because you've played so many different
positions, uh, what NFL players did you
admire or grow up watching?
>> No, definitely 100%. I'd say I I just
always was um evolving. Like I always
took the weight room very serious. So I
was always in the weight room and my
body just kept getting bigger and bigger
and I always took my nutrition serious.
So I was eating as many calories as
possible and I just ended up evolving
and coming to the point where I am now.
Id say the people that always like that
I really inspire and watch is like
Jaylen Carter, Fletcher Cox, and um
Grady Jarrett. So those are definitely,
you know, Coach Simpson was my defensive
line coach at Georgia Tech and he would
show a lot of tape um of um um of like
when he was at the Falcons. So that's
something that because he was the
Falcons Dline coach that we used to
watch his teach tape all the time and
that's something that I aspire to be
like one day.
>> Uh how do you feel about Grady Jarrett
being here?
>> I'm excited. You know, I'm excited to
learn. You know, my my coach was able to
coach him when he was at um when he was
the Falcons defensive line coach. So, I
can't wait to absorb all the information
from him, sir.
>> Awesome. Thank you so much.